University of Connecticut, Phi Kappa Phi Records 1995.0054
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Phi Kappa Phi Records
1951-1994
1995.0054
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
0.5 Linear feet
Petition to receive a charter from the Honor Society Phi Kappa Phi was begun and the local chapter organized in 1951. The Society itself was organized in 1897 to recognize and encourage superior scholarship in all academic disciplines. Admission is by invitation only and requires nomination and approval by a local chapter
Meade, Arland. [Collector.]
History
Petition to receive a charter from the Honor Society Phi Kappa Phi was begun and the local chapter at the University of Connecticut organized in 1951. The Society itself was organized in 1897 to recognize and encourage superior scholarship in all academic disciplines. Admission is by invitation only and requires nomination and approval by a local chapter.
Scope and Content
The collection contains the petition from the University, one piece of correspondence and the Society programs from 1961-1994.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
For Academic Excellence. A history of Chapter 59, Phi Kappa Phi, University of Connecticut. Dodd Call No.
Acquisition Information
Materials were collected and transferred by Arland Meade, emeritus faculty member.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Connecticut Societies, etc.—Education.; Education Societies, etc.; Greek letter societies—Connecticut.; Manuscripts.; Phi Kappa Phi. Connecticut Chapter (University of Connecticut).; Universities and colleges—Societies, etc.; University of Connecticut Societies, etc.
- Series I: Records, 1951-1994
  - Petition, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1961-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series II: 2013 Transfer, 1952-1995 (Box 1)
  - Annual Financial report, 1952-1972
  - Annual reports to National, 1956-1969
  - Minutes, 1951-1959
  - Constitution, 1960
  - Minutes, 1960-1968
  - History, undated, 1995-1996
  - History and related correspondence (nORTHBY), undated, 1995-1996
  - History and related correspondence (Veillette), undated, 1995
  - Correspondence, 1995
  - Members, undated, 1986
  - Correspondence, 1996
  - Correspondence (Thornton), 1996
  - Membership roster, 1951-1972
  - Correspondence, 1974, 1986
  - Treasurer (McCabe), undated